grade_6_part_1 = {
    "Ratios": [
        {
            "Part to whole ratio": {
            "Definition": "A part-to-whole ratio compares one part to the whole. For example, if there are 12 dogs and 8 cats, but no other animals, in a shelter, the part-to-whole ratio of dogs to animals is 12:(12+8), or 12:20, or 3:5.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "At the newest animated movie, for every 9 children, there are 4 adults. There are a total of 39 children and adults at the movie. How many children are at the movie?",
                        "Answer": "Since 9 + 4 = 13, the ratio is made up of 13 people. So the part to whole ratio of children to people is 9:13. So there are 39 * 9/13 = 27 children at the movie.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Part to part ratio": {
            "Definition": "A part-to-part ratio compares two parts of a whole.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Sara spents 2 hours at soccer pratice, 3 hours at a birthday party, 1 hour at a science project. What is the ratio of hours spent at soccer practice to the total hours spent at the birthday party and the science project?",
                        "Answer": "The total hours at the birthday party and the science project is 3 + 1 = 4 hours. So the ratio is 2:4 or 1:2.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
     "Arithmetic with rational numbers":[
        {
            "Dividing decimals": {
            "Definition": "To divide decimals by decimals, we need to make the divisor a whole number first. We do this by moving the decimal point in both the divisor and the dividend the same number of times to the right, until the divisor has no decimal point. This works because we are creating equivalent fractions.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Jenny makes 0.42 dollars a day.\nHow many days does it take so that she could reach 30.24 dollars?",
                        "Answer": "We need to obtain 30.24 / 0.42.\nBy shifting the decimal 2 places to the right, we would want to calculate 3024 / 42, which is 72. So Jenny needs 72 days.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Adding and subtracting decimals":{
            "Definition": "When we add or subtract decimals, we need to line up the decimal points to make sure we are adding or subtracting the same place values.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "David has 37.279 dollars, Bob has 5.4 dollars. In total, how much money do they have?",
                        "Answer": "The total money they have is 37.279 + 5.4 = 42.679.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Rates and percentages":[
        {
            "Unit rates":{
            "Definition": "A unit rate of two quantities in a ratio is the number of units of the first quantity for every 1 unit of the second quantity.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A box of 15 cookies costs \$ 9.\nWhat is the cost for 1 cookie?",
                        "Answer": "The cost for 1 cookie is 9 / 15 = 0.6 dollar.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Rates":{
            "Definition": "A rate is a ratio that compares two quantities with different units of measure.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A plane flew at a constant speed and traveled 762 miles in 5 hours. How many miles would the plane travel in 3 hours at the same speed?",
                        "Answer": "In 2 hour, the plane can travel 762 / 5 = 152.4 miles.\nSo in 3 hours, the plane can travel 152.4 * 3 = 457.2 miles.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Percent":{
            "Definition": "A percent is a way of expressing a part of a whole as a fraction out of 100.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "In the United States, 13 out of every 20 cans are recycled. What percent of cans are recycled?",
                        "Answer": "We can divide by 20 to figure out that 1 can represents 5% of the total amount of cans.\nSo 13 cans represent 5% * 13 = 65% of the cans.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
    ],
    "Exponents and order of operations":[
        {
            "Intro to exponents":{
            "Definition": "Exponents are a way of writing repeated multiplication. For example, instead of writing 2*2*2*2, we can write 2^4. The number 2 is called the base, and the number 4 is called the exponent.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is the volume of a cube with side length 3 m?",
                        "Answer": "The volume of the cube is: 3 * 3 * 3 = 3^3 = 27 m^3.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Order of operations":{
            "Definition": "The order of operations are one set of agreements for how to evaluate expressions. They make sure everyone gets to the same value.\nGrouping: We evaluate what's inside grouping symbols first, before anything else.\nExponents: We evaluate exponents before multiplying, dividing, adding, or subtracting.\nMultiplication and Division: We multiply and divide before we add or subtract.\nAddition and Subtraction: Lastly, we add and subtract.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Evaluate the following expression: 8^3 - 9 * 2 / 3.",
                        "Answer": "Firstly, there is no grouping, so we evaluate the exponent first and get: 8^3 = 512.\nNext, we evaluate the multiplication and division: 9 * 2 / 3 = 6.\nCombining them by subtraction, we obtain the final answer: 8^3 - 9 * 2 / 3 = 512 - 6 = 506.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Negative numbers":[
        {
            "Intro to negative numbers":{
            "Definition": "Negative numbers are numbers that are less than zero. They have a negative sign (âˆ’) in front of them.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A bank uses positive numbers to represent deposits and negative numbers to represent withdrawals. How would a bank represent a withdrawal of 19.43 dollars?",
                        "Answer": "We could represent it as -19.43 dollars.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Ordering negative numbers":{
            "Definition": "Numbers farther to the right (or farther up, on a vertical number line) are greater than numbers that are farther left (or down) on the same line.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Clarissa has 5 dollars, Jack has 10 dollars, while Bob owns 3 dollars and Alice owns 1.5 dollars. Order this group of friend from the richest to the poorest",
                        "Answer": "The money they correspondingly have are 5, 10, -3 and -1.5 dollars.\nAs the numbers farther to the right are greater, we can order the friends as follow: Jack, Clarissa, Alice, Bob.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Absolute value":{
            "Definition": "Absolute value is the distance of a number from zero on the number line. It is always a positive number or zero.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Luke weights 165 pounds while Maguire weights 150 pounds. How much does Maguire weight less than Luke?",
                        "Answer": "Maguire weights |150 - 165| = |-15| = 15 pounds less than Luke.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Variables and expressions":[
        {
            "Writing expressions with variables":{
            "Definition": "An algebraic expression is a combination of numbers, variables, and operations that shows a mathematical relationship.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Daniel makes 100 dollars each week. He worked for x weeks this summer.\nHow much money did Daniel make this summer?\nWrite your answer as an expression.",
                        "Answer": "The expression is: 100x.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Substitution and evaluating expressions":{
            "Definition": "To evaluate an algebraic expression means to find its value when we know the values of the variables.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "The expression 2m + 10c gives the amount of money, in dollars, a dessert store makes from selling m muffins and c cakes. How much money does the dessert store make from selling three muffins and four cakes?",
                        "Answer": "By substituting m = 3 and c = 4, the expression we need to evaluate becomes 2 * 3 + 10 * 4 = 46.\nSo the total amount of money the dessert store makes is 46 dollars.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Least common multiple":{
            "Definition": "LCM stands for least common multiple. The least common multiple of two numbers is the smallest number that is a multiple of both of them.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is the least common multiple of 3 and 4?",
                        "Answer": "We can write down the multiples of 4 until we find a number divisible by 3: 4, 8, 12, 16, ...\nThe first number that is divisible by 3 is 12, so lcm(3, 4) = 12.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Greatest common factor":{
            "Definition": "GCF stands for greatest common factor. The greatest common factor of two numbers is the greatest number that is a factor of both of them.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is the greatest common factor of 8 and 14?",
                        "Answer": "Factors of 8: 1, 2, 4, 8.\nFactors of 14: 1, 2, 7, 14\nCommon factors of both numbers: 1, 2.\nSo the greatest common factor is 2.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Combining like terms":{
            "Definition": "Like terms are terms that have the same variable and the same exponent. We can combine like terms by adding their coefficients. The coefficient is the number in front of the variable.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Combine the like terms to create an equivalent expression of 5z - 3 + 3z.",
                        "Answer": "The like terms that we can combine are 5z and 3z.\nSo after combining them, the expression becomes 8z - 3.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ]
}

grade_6_part_2 = {
    "Equations and inequalities":[
        {
            "One-step equations":{
            "Definition": "An equation is a statement that two expressions are equal. The value of the variable that makes a true equation is called a solution to the equation.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Mu is walking laps to raise money for charity. For each lap she walks, her sponsors will donate \$ 7. Mu has walked l laps and raised a total of $105. How many laps has Mu walked?",
                        "Answer": "The equation to describe this situation is: 7l = 105.\nSolving this equation, we obtain l = 15.\nSo Mu has walked 15 laps.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
    ],
    "Plane figures":[
        {
            "Areas of parallelograms":{
            "Definition": "The area of a parallelogram is the product of the length of the base and the height, or A = bh.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A parallelogram has an area of 20 cm^2 and is 4 cm in height. Find its base length.",
                        "Answer": "Let the parallelogram's base length be b cm.\nBy the formula of the parallelogram's area, we have: 20 = 4b.\nSolving this equation, we obtain b = 5.\nSo the base length is 5 cm.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Areas of triangles":{
            "Definition": "The area of a triangle is 1/2 the product of the length of the base and the height, or A = 1/2 bh.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Let ABC be an acute triangle with area 15 cm^2.\nLet H be a point on segment BC such that AH is perpendicular to BC.\nIf BC = 5 cm, what is the length of AH?",
                        "Answer": "Let AH = h cm.\nBy the formula of the triangle's area, we have: 15 = 5h.\nSolving this equation, we obtain h = 3.\nSo the length of AH is 3 cm.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Area of composite shapes":{
            "Definition": "A composite figure is a shape that is made up of two or more simpler shapes, like rectangles, triangles, circles, or other polygons. To find the area of a composite figure, we can use one of these strategies:\nSplit the composite figure into smaller shapes that we know how to find the area of, and then add up the areas of the smaller shapes, or\nSubtract the area of the unwanted parts from the area of a larger shape that contains the composite figure, or\nUse a formula or a rule that applies to the composite figure, if we know one.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Find the area of the shape ABCDE plotted below.\nBEGIN PLOT:\nDraw('A', (1, 1))\nDraw('B', (1, 19))\nDraw('C', (10, 13))\nDraw('D', (16, 13))\nDraw('E', (16, 1))\nEND PLOT.",
                        "Answer": "By extending the segment DC until it cuts AB at F, we have divided the figure into two parts: triangle BCF and rectangle AFDE.\nThe area of triangle BCF is 6 * 9 / 2 = 27 square units.\nThe area of rectangle AFDE is 12 * 15 = 180 square units.\nIn total, the area of the figure is 180 + 27 = 207 square units.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Coordinate plane": [
        {
            "Four quadrants":{
            "Definition": "The coordinate plane is a flat surface that has two number lines that cross at a point called the origin. The number line that goes left and right is called the x-axis, and the number line that goes up and down is called the y-axis. The x-axis and the y-axis divide the plane into four regions called quadrants. We label each quadrant with a Roman numeral in counterclockwise order: I, II, III or VI.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Among the four quadrants, where is the point (6,1) located on the coordinate plane?",
                        "Answer": "The point (6, 1) is located on the first quadrant.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Distance on the coordinate plane along an axis":{
            "Definition": "When the two points share an x- or y-coordinate, this means that they are either on the same horizontal line or on the same vertical line.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is the distance between points (-6, 8) and (-6, -3) on the coordinate plane?",
                        "Answer": "The two points share the same x-coordinate, so they are on the same vertical line.\nTheir distance is therefore: |8 - (-3)| = 11.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Polygons on the coordinate plane":{
            "Definition": "For perimeter, we will need to find the length of every side, then add all of the lengths. For the area of basic shapes, we often only need the length of the base and the height of the figure. We always measure the height at a perpendicular to the base. The area of a rectangle is the product of the length of the base times the height. For more complicated figures, we might need to split it into many rectangles. The total area will be the sum of the areas of all of the rectangles.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Rectangle ABCD is graphed in the coordinate plane. The following are the vertices of the rectangle: A(2,0), B(6,0), C(6,7), and D(2,7). What is the area of rectangle ABCD?",
                        "Answer": "The length of side AB is: 6 - 2 = 4.\nThe length of side AD is: 7 - 0 = 7.\nSo the area of the rectangle is: 4 * 7 = 28.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
    ],
    "3D figures": [
        {
            "Volume with fractions":{
            "Definition": "Sometimes, the length, width, or height of a rectangular prism might not be a whole number, but a fraction.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "The Jones family is moving, and they need a truck with at least 40 cubic meters of space. The moving trucks they have to choose from are shown below:\nSmall truck: Length 4 m, width 3 m, height 3 1/2 m.\nMedium truck: Length 5 m, width 3 1/3 m, height 4m.\nLarge truck: Length 6 1/4 m, width 4 m, height 4 m.\nWhich is the smallest truck that they can use?",
                        "Answer": "The volume of the small truck is: 4 * 3 * 7/2 = 42 m^3.\nThe volume of the medium truck is: 5 * 10/3 * 4 = 66 2/3 m^3.\nThe volume of the large truck is: 25/4 * 4 * 4 = 100 m^3.\nSince the small truck has volume larger than 40 m^3 and has the smallest volume, we choose the small truck.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Surface area":{
            "Definition": "The surface area of a 3D figure is the total area of all its faces.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Andrea has a rectangular box with height 10 cm, width 5 cm and length 7 cm.\nWhat is the area of colorful tapes (in m^2) she must buy in order to wrap the whole box?",
                        "Answer": "The surface area of the rectangular box is: 2 * (10 * 5 + 5 * 7 + 7 * 10) = 310 m^2.\nSo Andrea needs to buy 310 m^2 of colorful tapes.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
    ],
    "Data and statistics": [
        {
            "Mean":{
            "Definition": "The mean is the average of all the data values, which we find by adding them all up and dividing by how many there are.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Liam works at a zoo. He was looking at some data showing the masses of their 5 African elephants. The mean mass of the elephants was 3,800kg. The smallest elephant, named Lola, weighed 2,700kg. Lola then got very sick and lost weight until her mass reached 1,800kg. How will Lola's mass decreasing affect the mean?",
                        "Answer": "Lola's weight lost a total of 2,700 - 1,800 = 900 kg.\nHence, the total weigh of 5 elephants also decreases by 900 kg.\nThus, the average weight decreases by 900 / 5 = 180 kg.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Median":{
            "Definition": "The median is the middle value of the data, which we find by putting them in order from smallest to largest and picking the one in the middle (or the average of the two in the middle, if there are an even number of values).",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "The following data points represent the number of slices of pizza that each person at Thorton's birthday party ate: 7, 9, 3, 2, 4, 3, 1.\nFind the median number of slices.",
                        "Answer": "Sorting the data from least to greatest: 1, 2, 3, 3, 4, 7, 9.\nThe middle point is the number 3.\nSo the mediam number of slices is 3.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Interquatile range":{
            "Definition": "The interquartile range is the difference between the middle 50% of the data, which we find by dividing the data into four equal parts (called quartiles) and subtracting the first quartile from the third quartile.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "The following data points represent the number of classes that each teacher at Broxin High School teaches: 5, 9, 1, 3, 4, 1, 5, 7, 6, 4, 5.\nFind the interquatile range of the dataset.",
                        "Answer": "Sorting the data from least to greatest: 1, 1, 3, 4, 4, 5, 5, 5, 6, 7, 9.\nThe median is 5.\nQ1 = 3 is the median of the data to the left of the median.\nQ3 = 6 is the median of the data to the right of the median.\nSo IQR = Q3 - Q1 = 6 - 3 = 3.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Mean absolute deviation":{
            "Definition": "The mean absolute deviation is the average of how far each value is from the mean, which we find by subtracting the mean from each value, taking the absolute value (which means ignoring the negative sign), adding them all up, and dividing by how many there are.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "The following lines show the number of snow days each school district in Mill County had last winter:\nDistrict 200: 6 snow days.\nDistrict 211: 8 snow days.\nDistrict 221: 3 snow days.\nDistrict 231: 2 snow days.\nDistrict 241: 6 snow days.\nFind the mean absolute deviation of the dataset.",
                        "Answer": "The mean of the dataset is: (6 + 8 + 3 + 2 + 6) / 5 = 5.\nThe absolute deviations are: 1, 3, 2, 3, 1.\nSo the mean absolute deviation is: (1 + 3 + 2 + 3 + 1) / 5 = 2.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ]
}